Hi. I'm Marc.
I’m a product manager here at Tessl working on Tessl code review.
And I'm here with my colleague Colin, who will introduce himself.
Hi I'm Colin.
I'm a software engineer here at Tessl.
I built a lot of the architecture of code review.
Perfect. Thanks, Colin.
And today we're going to be taking you through Tessl Code review, telling you
a little bit about it, how it works, how you can set it up for yourself,
and how you can customize it for your organization.
Along the way, we'll also talk a bit about Tessl and software factories,
and where code review fits in software factories and a lot more.
Bear in mind we'll be keeping some time at the end
to answer your questions, so feel free to drop them into the chat as we go along.
We'll make sure that we have a look at them at the end
and get through everyone's questions with that.
Should we get stuck in? Let's do it. Cool.
So before
I get started with Tessl code review,
let me just take a few moments to talk about what is Tessl,
especially for those of you not familiar with what we do.
Tessl is building tools to help
you build your software factory.
Now, we've been doing this for ourselves for a couple of years already,
and one of the things we've learned is that building
a software factory isn't just about building the plumbing.
It's actually quite straightforward to build the necessary steps
to take an issue to an agent, to generate code and create a PR.
What's really difficult is for that PR to actually have code
you can trust, code you're willing to merge into your code base.
And so with that in mind, Tessl's learned along the way that in order
to build trustworthy code with an agent, you need to have the right context.
And so for a long time, Tessl has worked on managing context,
building tools to inventory the context that you have in your repo
to evaluate how good it is, and make sure that you're
always improving the context that's in that repo.
And in doing that on our own repo, we started to
learn it's not just about building a context,
but building loops on top of that context, because any context you build
is going to start rotting almost straight away.
And the longer you leave it untouched,
the more damage that it might actually cause to your agent over time.
And so by building self-improvement loops on top of context
loops that look at the context check when the last time it was updated
evaluated to see if it's still the context
is still relevant for the repo, for the code, for the
the work that the agent is doing, but also observing the code
that is being generated, the PR that are being merged and checking
if they are correct, if they are starting to fail,
if there are signs that things are starting to go wrong.
By observing these things, you can then act on them and go back to the repo.
Go back to the skills and improve that context.
And this self-improvement loop means your skills don't go stale.
Your agents always have the best possible context
and therefore are producing the highest quality code.
And what we found
when doing this for ourselves over the course of a long period of time,
is that a collection of loops that build on top of each other
and actually feed into each other and work on your SDLC
is essentially a factory, but one that's tuned to your repo
and your organization the way you and your team work.
And so Tessl's building not just tools for managing context,
but also increasingly managing loops.
And where we're getting to is composing and building your factory as well.
Now if we look at the software development lifecycle
from issue creation to production level code, as I mentioned,
there are multiple different loops in that flow that we can think about.
I'm not going to go through them today.
We're going to focus on one particular loop,
which occurs at the end of that flow, which is the code review improvement loop.
Now, code review is arguably one of the most essential steps
in a factory, because it doesn't matter
what your agent is doing in code creation, if it's producing low quality code
that is unable to be approved
by an agent, you can have to have a human come in and clean up the mess.
The.
And when humans are coming in to clean up the mess, then you're turning software
engineers into full time reviewers and nobody wants to do that.
So the more we can get agent code review to be useful and to catch those issues,
but also to feed back into the factory to make it better so those issues
don't surface in the first place.
That's the job we're trying to do here.
And so that's what we're going to be talking about today.
So as we
were building our own factory and building up our context
and exploring these loops and so on, one of the things we found from using
a variety of different code review tools was they didn't quite fit
the Tessl philosophy of the factory being composed of skills and loops.
We found that a lot of our tools we were using were black boxes.
There was no way to build a self-improvement loop on them.
We were discovering all these issues with code generation
and context, and creating skills and plugins to help address that.
But our code review is still the same old code review we were using.
And so we were increasingly thinking about how to make code review
a part of the context, a part of the
the Tessl structure that can be self improved as we go along.
And with that, that meant we ended up building our own code review.
We ran it over several months and built it up over time
to address our needs and to make it fit the factory native way of thinking.
And got to a point where we were finding
Tessl's code review was detecting
defects in in pairs
at a rate of around 74%, compared to the 50%
rate that we were seeing at the beginning of of working on this.
And one of the reasons we see such a significant jump in the
ability of our code review to find defects is because we have this self-improvement
built into it, and this ability to customize based on the skills
that power Tessl code review, that,
you know,
the code review we're doing here is very fine tuned to our repo and our way
of working, and also feeds into the skills we're using to write
the code in the first place.
And we believe this isn't something that's only Tessl specific.
This is something any organization can benefit from.
And so the way we've built Tessl code review is at a very high level.
And Collins going to talk us through the details here in a few moments.
But we take a pull request.
We run it through the Tessl code review GitHub app.
We have a set of skills that do the code review a set of four different skills
that look at the the pull requests from a couple of different angles.
You get four out of the box, but the idea is that it's very easy
to customize either those four skills or to add your own skills on top of that.
And in fact, Tessl has ended up building three additional Tessl
specific skills that have come about through our self-improvement loops.
And so these seven skills are part of our code review
and our selective selected depending on the PR.
And then the output from that is of course,
the findings from the code review, which end up as a comment on the PR,
and also a mechanism for approving or requesting changes on the PR.
So we're going to be covering
all this and more over the next 20, 30 minutes.
We're going to show you what a Tessl code review looks like.
The pull request looks like.
We'll walk you through how to set it up and how easy it is,
how to configure it and customize it, and what a custom
code review lens looks like, at least for Tessl.
And what I might look like for you.
And then at the end, I'll show you, talk a bit about what's coming next,
and we'll make sure this in time for questions.
With that, I'm going to hand it over to Colin who's
going to walk us through Tessl code review.
Great. Thank you. Mark.
You should all be able to see my screen now.
So for this webinar,
I've vibe coded a little project that I've had in mind for a while.
It's an ambient music generator
based on my PC's current performance and stats.
I like music and I like vibe coding, so it's a nice synergy of things I love.
Does it get more intense or like more relaxing as things heat up?
Definitely more intense, but it's ambient, so it's never super intense.
It's always quite relaxing. So.
So, yeah.
What are you looking at?
Here is a pull request.
And made some changes.
I've introduced atmospheric atmospheric sub base, pulse generator.
Kind of essential. And
you can see Tessl reviewer has
approved the changes, but it's left some optional suggestions.
So let's have a look at them.
Minor
thing about telemetry.
And another one here.
So he's.
So talk us through what's happened here.
You know, what's the flow that this has gone through to get at what you're seeing?
Yeah.
So essentially I've opened a PR and this runs automatically
when the PR opens and it looks
through the changes and identifies the misuse.
And I'll come to
how I've configured
what changes are being looked at and how they're being looked at in a second.
And then leaves a comment and then I can choose to fix them.
I can choose to ignore them,
I can choose to say they're not true, but mostly they're they're pretty solid.
And so you can see I've fixed it here
and I've rerun the review and it says, yes, you've addressed it.
Well done.
And I've invoked using this command here Tessl code review.
And next one it says cool.
Your changes have addressed our findings.
Good to merge.
And that's essentially the the process from a PR perspective.
And you can see being GitHub app we have the native checks.
Approve can also request changes.
And yeah so that's what that looks like.
So how do you install this.
It's actually super easy.
So you go to your Tessl.io org page and your integrations.
You can literally just install the integration manager on GitHub.
And then you have a few configuration options which I'll talk through.
So just before you get there, for those who maybe haven't installed
Tessl yet or who are new, it's really straightforward, right?
To install Tessl, how would you go about getting to this stage?
Yeah, totally.
So you can install the Tessl CLI
and then you can just run Tessl agent,
which is our own agent that will guide you how to do all this stuff.
You can also just go to create an account and you'll have access to it super easy.
And at that point, all you need to do is install the GitHub app on this page.
And almost good to go.
So the next part would be configuring it.
So these are how and when it runs.
So I've decided when it's opened or been mentioned.
But you can also have it run on every push.
If you want.
You can set the review behavior so you can enforce it.
So this will approve or block pull requests or advisory.
If you just want to kind of
test the waters with with it.
Would you recommend if you're trying Tessl code review for the first time,
maybe to switch it into advisory just to get a feel for it?
I would say no, put it in forcing.
But, you know, I've used it a lot.
So yeah, for a first year, if you want to just kind of dip your toes, the water,
see how it would do, definitely put it on, let it run for a bit. See.
See how you find it.
Yeah.
And the last option here is auto approve after all Tessl threads are resolved.
So this is click resolve on all the threads.
Leave a message and it will approve your PR.
Yeah.
So that's pretty much all it is to set it up.
And that's configurable per repo.
As well. Exactly.
So right now I just have a single repository here,
but I can add more and I can configure it more differently.
So they can have different rules for how you, how they run.
So yeah that's how you add the app.
But the cool part is how to kind of configure the the review itself.
So here I've got my review
audio DSP and synthesis engine skill.
So this is a skill that specifically talks about how to review code.
That is to do with audio processing and audio signal processing.
I won't go into the nerdy details, but
for example, glitch and pop prevention must fix.
So yeah, finding issues where the audio being generated
has is clipping or popping.
These are bugs that must be flagged.
This is really cool
because obviously this app is all about generating ambient sound.
Don't want any glitches or pops.
I want smooth ambient.
Does the kind of thing you wouldn't have instructions about this kind of stuff in a
out of the box code review, because it's so specific to music generation in.
This case.
Yeah, exactly.
And what was cool is I created this lens with Tessl agent.
I said, hey, Tessl agent, look at my current code base, suggest
some good lenses that will catch the bugs that I care about.
And came up with this, which was really great.
When you say, look at your code base, what was it looking at in the code base?
So looking at the source code was also looking at some of my
Readme docs, some major MDS trying to assess
what are my kind of best practices, what are the things to look for.
And also, you know, putting in best practices
for audio signal processing, which there are many.
Yeah. And it came up with this and then
we're all kind of glues together.
Is this YAML file where we can,
do some cool stuff, where we can firstly configure how strict we want it.
So I've set relaxed mode because let's be real, this is a vibe code project.
No one else is ever going to see it for you guys.
Of course.
But I didn't want to be too strict.
But here's the cool part.
Under lenses, you can pass a ref to your lens
and you can say under what path it runs in.
So I only want my audio DSP lens to run under source audio,
because I wouldn't want this lens to run against stuff that,
you know, is not to do with audio, because it'd be irrelevant.
And you can go super deep with this, have a whole bunch of nested lenses
running at very specific points in in your code base to have very,
yeah, specific reviews, both for your repository,
but also for the area being looked at.
And yeah, that's kind of what it is.
So you run that and you get reviews.
So just jumping back to this page, you can see this
review came from a little text here audio DSP.
So that lens will tell you which lens caught which bug.
And the last bit is outside of GitHub altogether.
You can also run it directly on your CLI.
So I've already run it here.
So Tessl code review give it the profile that's just showed you run
that against your local unsaved changes and it'll tell you what to do.
So this is a nice way to iterate locally before opening the PR even.
Got it.
So if you just want to get a feel for how it works,
it's really easy to come here and run
this sort of ad hoc review and see what kind of output there is.
Yeah, totally.
And it's really useful, especially if you have an agent working on your code.
You can say, run the review a few times before opening the PR to hopefully catch
the majority of the issues before it even reaches GitHub.
And would this be a good mechanism for if you are writing a custom lens
to test it out?
Yeah, totally. I mean, you can iterate locally like this.
I can make changes to my lens right here, rerun the review and
yeah, see us catching what I wanted to catch,
you know, do this in a loop and kind of improve it yourself.
And just to, to take a few more moments to talk about these customized lenses,
because I think this is really one of the key differentiators
with Tessl's code review, the fact that you can fine
tune it to how you and your organization like to work.
Could you tell us a little bit more, for a start, about the default
lenses that ship with this and what they each doing?
Yeah, totally.
And actually, let me show you the default lenses.
Because they're actually really cool.
We spent a long time tuning these.
Here they are.
And so you're showing us here, these are available in our public repo.
Yes, exactly.
So we ship with four lenses by default that run.
So if I was to run here without giving the the
the profile, it would run with these four default lenses.
And there we spent a long time tuning them.
And actually you can see them right here.
So we have four lenses here correctness and data integrity.
Security and privacy scale and resilience, maintainability and code quality.
And we felt this combination of four covers
the vast majority of vanilla use cases for any code base,
no matter what language, what frameworks, anything like that.
And yeah, super solid.
And yeah, these defaults, you're good to go.
But what I'm excited about is the kind of custom lenses that you can do.
Yeah.
And talk us through then the custom lens that you just showed us.
What was the process you went to
to create that for, you know, this, this vibe repo.
Vibe repo.
So, yeah, like I said, I used the Tessl agent.
Maybe I can just show you right here.
So, agent,
So I can say,
help me create a new custom lens for my
vibe project.
And essentially, this is all it is.
We won't go for all of this, but, yeah,
there's a skill that directs the agent how to do this.
It'll read through everything.
And then the the result is
a pretty bespoke lens
that is directly related to your code base and your best practices.
Of course, you can tune it further as you go.
And that's where this nice local iteration comes in as well.
Got it.
And the key thing here is that we've built,
a skill in our registry that's available in the agent as well.
Or you can install it into whatever agent you're using to not only set up
code review, Tessl code review, but also to
then create custom lenses as and when you want to.
Yeah, exactly.
And yeah, like I said, there's a lot of configurability there.
And as you go into it more,
you'll probably find that you want to configure it even further.
And the more you configure it kind of more valuable.
I think it becomes to your stock.
Brilliant.
And that gives us a, that brings us
to where we are today with the Tessl code review product.
It's currently live in beta.
It's still actively being developed, but,
we are planning to launch it out of beta next week.
We're going to be at AI DevCon in New York.
And with that, we'll be taking it out of beta.
We're also going to be introducing our first public self-improvement loop.
So the lens that Colin was talking about, the mechanism
that you go through in order to create that right now,
you can do it with the beta as a manual, ad hoc thing, but we'll be introducing the
ability to schedule that and have that be something that runs on a regular basis.
And so you can set it up one time and it will be self improving over time.
And this is the first
of many such self-improvement loops that we're going to be introducing,
not just for Tessl code review, but for across Tessl's product suite in general.
And as I mentioned at the start, we believe it's that composition of loops
that you build up over time on top of the skills that you have in your repo
that will eventually help you build your factory.
And so with that, I think we've covered everything.
We have some time for questions.
I'm just going to have a look to see
what's come through.
I've got a question here.
How does it handle really large PRs
or mono repos?
Yeah. So
if you just use a vanilla, it does pretty well.
But what's exciting and what's cool about
this is the custom globs that you can have for your lenses.
So of course, you might have a mono repo with tens to hundreds different projects
in that you don't want necessarily one lens to be on all of them.
So you can say, well, if this piece of code attaching the back
end or system, there's this particular lens for that.
So it becomes very specific.
So you kind of break down a very large PR into smaller sections
that can then be reviewed by the lens specific to that section.
Got it.
So you want to avoid you don't want to have
the same set of lenses for every single PR.
You want to make sure you are fine tuning it in that way.
And I guess that's also the strength of.
You could feasibly have ten dozens of lenses
on a sufficiently large repo, but if you are then dictating
where they are active, you're not going to be overloading
your agent with trying to review every, every PR in every possible way.
That makes sense.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly.
The kind of a hierarchy of lenses, right?
You might have one lens that is for everything.
There is some very specific rule that goes across the organization.
But then you might have lenses at a very specific
that you would only want to run on certain things.
And it's kind of up to you how you configure it.
And so we've got another question here,
but I think we may have answered it inadvertently.
Can I choose different review lenses for different repos or types of change.
Yeah.
So firstly for different repos, every repo can have a different profile
with a different set of custom lenses.
But yeah, like I said, you can totally configure
different lenses for different parts of the code base.
And I should mention you can also configure the effort level
in which they run.
So you can have a
very simple review lens
running at low effort or a very complicated lens,
or very like critical path type lens running at a high effort.
And that's another degree of configuration you have.
And there's all globs scoped, which is cool.
Perfect.
I've got one more question here.
How many rounds does it do per PR.
So it depends on the size of the PR.
Yeah.
Bit of a how long are the piece of string question.
But on average in our monitoring and we run it on I think
good — three to four thousand plus PRs —
is we're looking at 2 to 3 rounds per PR.
Some big complicated changes might take longer.
You might be making changes as you go.
Some symbol changes will be one round and it's good to go.
But yeah roughly 2 to 3 rounds per pair.
Got it. Cool.
Well I think that brings us to the end.
Thank you so much, Colin.
And thank you for for watching and for sharing your questions.
If you're interested in trying out
Tessl code review, it's really easy to get started.
Simply type into your CLI Tessl install code
review, that's Tessl install code review or visit our website.
And you'll see how to sign up for Tessl.
And our onboarding will walk you through the code review setup process.
Anyway,
thanks for watching.
Thank you.